TIM CHRISTIE

Experienced Data Analyst with a passion for Augmented Reality and Data Visualization. Skilled in R and Python, with an ability to produce engaging data products and research.

San Francisco Bay Area contact@timothychristie.com (650) 387-6484 timothychristie.com

EXPERIENCE

QuanticMind | Senior Data Analyst (Customer Success Team)

NOVEMBER 2018 - JULY 2019 | REDWOOD CITY / SAN MATEO, CALIFORNIA

Responsibilities and projects have included:

- → Customer Interactions: Worked directly with clients to troubleshoot bidding performance for their advertising programs. Set up and assessed performance of new customer pilot programs. Provided quarterly, and ad-hoc performance review slide decks to clients. Mapped client's business goals to bidding algorithm parameters.
- → **Data Products:** Provided various data products both internally and externally. These included charts generated in R, Excel spreadsheets, and dashboards created in the QuanticMind UI.
- → Internal Tools: Developed R Shiny framework to house internal data analysis tools for Customer Success Managers and Data Analysts on the Customer Success Team.

Meta | Data Analytics and Technical Services Engineer (Analytics and Neuroscience Team)

JULY 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2018 | SAN MATEO, CALIFORNIA

Responsibilities and projects have included:

- → **KPI Data:** Worked with the Executive team to define KPIs related to sales, marketing, and usage of Meta headsets. Developed a series of automated reports and web applications in R to deliver weekly reports.
- → **Data Pipeline:** Developed a combination of PostgreSQL databases, Python running on AWS, and off the shelf ETL products to automate internal data collection and aggregation.
- → SDK Analytics: Worked with the Product and SDK teams to define and implement analytics in the Meta 2 Unity SDK. Consumed this data and produced reports pertaining to customer engagement and retention.
- → Website and Marketing Analytics: Implemented and reported on web tracking on the metavision.com site.
- → User Research and Testing: Developed testing rigs to measure the focal plane, text legibility and field of view of Meta 2 prototypes. Built eye calibration app prototype in Unity for the Meta 2. Built an arcade scoreboard and API in Elixir to incentivize users and record their high scores in an internal test.
- → **Hackathons:** Competed in three internal hackathons. Most notably built a web server in Elixir to route traffic for a 3D video chat application.

SKILLS

Languages: Proficient in R, SQL, HTML, and CSS. Familiar with Python and Javascript. Completed projects in C# and Elixir.

Technologies: Excel, Git, AWS, PostgreSQL, Unity.

PUBLICATIONS

ISMAR 2016: Exploring Immersive AR Instructions for Procedural Tasks: The Role of Depth, Motion, and Volumetric Representations.

PROJECTS

Hackagong, July 2013:

Co-organizer for Australia's largest independent hackathon at the time. Responsibilities included organising event space, promotion, and prizes.

HackagongX Code, September 2013: Co-organized a second hackathon in 2013 with an emphasis on software development.

EDUCATION

University of Wollongong | Bachelor of Business Information Systems (Dean's Scholar)

2011 - 2013 | WOLLONGONG, AUSTRALIA

Graduated with Distinction. Subjects included: Database Management Systems, Web Technologies, Human Computer Interaction, Object Oriented Programming.